Guide to the Tsue Chong Wing Company records 1929-1933
Montana Historical Society Research Center
Tsue Chong Wing Company records>
1929-1933
Montana Historical Society, Research Center Archives Archives 225 N. Roberts PO Box 201201 Helena MT 59620-1201 (406) 444-2681 mhslibrary@mt.gov
A9:1-5
Tsue Chong Wing Company (Helena, Mont.)
.4 linear feet of shelf space
The Tsue Chong Wing Company was a Helena, Montana, general merchandise and grocery business (1895-1944) specializing in Chinese goods. The records (1920-1933) in this collection include bank statements, tax accessment records, bills, and invoices. In addition there are writings and letters (undated and in Chinese) possibly related to the purchase of merchandise from China and San Francisco. There are also records for members of the Wong family and for the Rose Garden Restaurant.
by series
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Chinese Americans--Montana--Helena.
General stores--Montana--Helena.
Helena (Mont.)--Commerce.
Montana
Chinese Americans
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Incoming Correspondence
  - Letters (in English), 1926-1938, 1957 (Box-folder 1 / 1)
  - Correspondence and writings (in Chinese: soome may be ads from suppliers), undated (Box-folder 1 / 2-3)
- Financial Records
  - Bank book: Tsue Chong Wing, 1931-1933 (Box-folder 1 / 4)
  - Bank exchanges to a bank in Hong Kong (possibly to pay for goods ordered), 1928-1929 (Box-folder 1 / 5)
  - Bank statements and cancelled checks: Tsue Chong Wing, 1927-1933 (Box-folder 1 / 6-7)
  - Bank statements and cancelled checks: Wong Gong Dick, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 1 / 8)
  - Bank statements and cancelled checks: Sang Wong, 1928-1931 (Box-folder 1 / 9)
  - Financial statement: Rose Garden Cafe, Helena (in Chinese), 1926? (Box-folder 1 / 10)
  - Freight bills, undated (Box-folder 1 / 11)
  - Invoices and bills: Rose Garden Cafe, 1926 (Box-folder 1 / 12-14)
  - Tax receipts and assessments: Tsue Chong Wing and Company; Wong Tsue, 1920-1922 (Box-folder 1 / 15)
- Legal Documents
  - Montana Dept. of Health license: Garden and Wong Restaurant, 1926 (Box-folder 1 / 16)
- Writings
  - Four notebooks of writings (in Chinese), n.d. (Box-folder 1 / 17)